Nafisa Ali Amir

3601 Greenway Unit 503, Baltimore, Maryland, 21218, USA

Mobile: +1 443 635 7255 • Email: amirnafisa@gmail.com • Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/amirnafisa

Webpage: https://amirnafisa.github.io

SUMMARY

Software Engineer

Computer science student with diverse background and rich experience in industry, research and academia. A natural language processing and deep learning enthusiast, able to work both independently and in a team, demonstrating motivation and multi-tasking abilities required to meet demanding deadlines while maintaining highest standards.

EDUCATION

Masters in Science and Engineering, Computer Science, Johns Hopkins University	2018-2020
Masters in Technology, Electronics Design and Tech, Indian Institute of Science	2010-2012
Bachelors in Engineering, Electronics and Telecommunication, Rajiv Gandhi Institute	2006-2010

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

Python • C • C++ • Perl • PyTorch • Numpy • Scipy

OTHER TECHNICAL SKILLS

Github • AWS • Google Colaboratory • Microsoft Office • SVN • Unit Testing

COURSES

Machine Learning • Deep Learning • Natural Language Processing • Parallel Programming • Information Retrieval and Web Agents • Vision as Bayesian Inference • Probability and Statistics • Data structures • Introduction to Algorithms • Processor Design

PROJECTS

Github: https://github.com/amirnafisa

•	Catchphrase extraction from legal documents	Apr 2019
•	Fine tuning and ensembling deep architectures in Resource Constrained Environment	Nov 2018
•	Earley Parsing and HMM based Tagging using Forward Backward and Viterbi Algorithm	Sep 2018
•	Cyber Physical System with Service Oriented Architecture	Aug 2012

PUBLICATION

Rao, I. H., Amir, N. A., Dagale, H., & Kuri, J. (2012, December). e-SURAKSHAK: A cyber-physical healthcare system with service oriented architecture. In Electronic System Design (ISED), 2012 International Symposium on (pp. 177-182). IEEE.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Research Associate, PRIME and APT, University of Manchester, Manchester, UK

Jun 2016 - Feb 2017

- The project was a part of PRiME in collaboration with Intel, Microsoft Research, University of Southampton
- Created firmware for ARM based microprocessor (Cortex M4) for testing and benchmark validations and for supporting spiking neural network applications

Research Student, Indian Institute of Science, Bengaluru, India

June 2011-May2012

• Designed, implemented and tested cyber physical healthcare systems with service oriented architecture

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Firmware Engineer, Automata Technologies, London, UK

Jan 2018 – Apr 2018

Designed, implemented and tested the firmware for robot's end effector

Design and Testing Engineer, Roamworks, Dubai, UAE

Aug 2014 - Jun 2016

 Designed, implemented, tested and launched an electronic communication interface for scada and fleet management systems

ASIC Design Engineer, Nvidia, Bengaluru, India

Aug 2012 - Feb 2014

 Worked on netlist verification and timing closure of CPUs and SOCs of Tegra processors while also implementing engineering change orders (ECOs) on pre and post layout netlist